

Sean Brent

Full-Stack Developer

Portfolio: seanbrent.ca



github.com/Brentsa



(905) 467-6136



seanbrent5@gmail.com



Oakville, Ontario, Canada

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTOCoding Bootcamp Certificate Feb 2021 – Aug 2021

- Full-Stack MERN developer
- Completed with a 95.5% average

MCMASTER UNIVERSITY

Honours Bachelor of Commerce Sept 2011 – Nov 2015

- Cumulative GPA of 9.9/12 (3.3 GPA)
- Achieved the Dean's Honour List in 2nd, 3rd, and 4th years

PRO. SKILLS

- JavaScript
- C++
- Git
- React
- Express
- Node.js
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- Sequelize
- Handlebars
- PWAs
- Python

- MySQL
- Redux
- GraphQL
- Apollo
- HTML
- CSS
- jQuery
- Jest
- Webpack
- IndexedDB
- JWT
- TDD

VOLUNTEERING

Enrolled in volunteer days with Bank of Montreal participating in activities such as food sorting, tree planting, and playground construction

Provided support as an Intern Event Coordinator to Mindshape Creative Brand Marketing representatives who were organizing the 2015 Ford Motor Company field conference

PROFILE

A full-stack web developer with a focus on the MERN stack of technologies. I have created entire progressive web applications and have participated in all phases of web development such as conception, planning, back-end, and front-end. I can write functional APIs with REST or GraphQL that utilize SQL or NoSQL databases. Conversely, I have extensive experience with React and Redux. I have written SPAs and myriad components that utilize global state, props, and hooks. Having worked on multiple team projects, I typically adopt a leadership role to bring the team's vision to life. I delegate responsibilities to my teammates, help debug code, and write my own assigned segments. I yearn to adopt novel technologies into my stack.

A self-taught C++ and game developer with experience in Unreal Engine 4. C++ endowed me with a firm understanding of object-oriented programming by utilizing concepts such as inheritance, encapsulation, and polymorphism. It also taught me about typical data structures, namely, dynamic arrays, lists, sets, and maps. In order to manipulate these containers, I employed and created efficient algorithms that followed the guidelines of big O notation. Lastly, C++ taught me about memory management and the functionality of pointers/references.

WORK EXPERIENCE

STRATEGIC GROWTH MANAGER

Bank of Montreal | Mississauga, ON

2021 - Current

- Managed the relationship of two referral programs by delicately balancing internal KPIs with the requirements of external partners
- Optimized program strategies and pricing to remain competitive in the industry to maximize deal referrals
- Solved issues raised by stakeholders to ensure deals were funded quickly and efficiently as possible while maintaining strict compliance
- Utilized inside sales representatives on the commercial team to facilitate deal funding

INSIDE SALES REPRESENTATIVE

Bank of Montreal | Mississauga, ON

2018 - 2021

- Assisted with the inception of two business referral programs
- Managed the day-to-day tasks of four referral accounts
- Prospered in a dynamic commercial sales environment by hastily assisting clients, account managers, internal functional teams, and referral partners while concurrently exceeding service expectations
- Developed the ability to comprehend and analyze financial statements

COSTING ANALYST

Allseating Corporation | Mississauga, ON

2017 - 2018

- Collaborated with sales representatives to craft competitive quotes for new business opportunities, ensuring profitability by manipulating discounts, commissions, and incentives
- Oversaw requests for special product modifications and ensured they were financially feasible
- Created product costing models to accurately display revenue, cost of goods sold, gross margin, and profit for each unit